<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 12:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/portfolio/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building an Image Similarity Model with Keras: My Bellsprout Moment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/blog/building-an-image-similarity-model-with-keras-my-bellsprout-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/blog/building-an-image-similarity-model-with-keras-my-bellsprout-moment/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this project, I set out to explore image similarity using deep learning. Leveraging the power of Keras, I aimed to detect similarities between images using a Pokémon image dataset from Kaggle. The idea was simple: take a pre-trained ResNet50 model, process Pokémon images into their vector forms, and then compare these vectors with an image of myself. The results? You&amp;rsquo;ll see soon enough.&#xA;The Dataset and Approach For this project, I used a Pokémon images dataset available on Kaggle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning using SQL?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/blog/machine-learning-using-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/blog/machine-learning-using-sql/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The journey of a thousand miles begins with one step.&amp;rdquo; — Lao Tzu&#xA;Yes, you read that one right! One of the most fundamental machine learning algorithms out there is Linear Regression. In simple words, it is a technique to describe a relationship between a response(a.k.a dependent) variable and one or more explanatory (a.k.a independent) variable(s). After doing some reading into the “math” behind these algorithms, I realized that this can be easily achieved in SQL.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
